AI may have finally killed the dreaded
cover letter. Now that AI can generate
highly personalized polished letters
within seconds, [music]
what was once a helpful hiring signal to
employers may now become obsolete.
McKinsey eliminated cover letters
[music] a few years ago. Google has not
required them for at least 5 years. BCG,
Boston Consulting Group, [music] stopped
requiring them in North America nearly a
decade ago. And Amazon's guidance to
applicants is relatively
straightforward. Keep your resume up to
date and skip the cover letter
altogether. Wharton's worth I spoke with
Wharton School economics professor Judd
Kessler [music] told me that hiring
research assistants has become a lot
harder. Not because there aren't great
candidates, [music] but because all of a
sudden everyone looks great on paper.
Kessler said he now has to rely more on
classroom performance, referrals,
[music] and recommendations. Recruiters
and hiring managers say that cover
letters have been losing importance for
years, [music] but that AI has
accelerated that shift. So, many
companies are now skipping them
altogether. Instead, employers are
looking for more direct evidence of
skills, like assessments, portfolios,
side projects, or verified credentials.
LinkedIn's head of global talent
acquisition, Aaron [music] Scruggs, told
me that the company is more interested
in seeing a candidate's skills
>> [music]
>> than reading about them. Cisco, which
also stopped requiring cover letters
years ago, says that the objective or
summary section at the top of a resume
is enough to show a candidate's [music]
fit for the role and background. So, if
you're applying for a job, the question
isn't whether your cover letter will
sway a hiring manager. Now, it's about
proving your skills. To read more about
the future of hiring in the AI era, head
to Business Insider. [music]